Guide to the Faculty of Engineering, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Faculty of Engineering, Yale University, records
1986-1994
RU 200
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
The records consist of administrative files documenting the academic and professional activities of the Faculty of Engineering at Yale.
Yale University. Faculty of Engineering
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative files documenting the academic and professional activities of the Faculty of Engineering at Yale.
Engineering -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Faculty of Engineering
- Yale University. Faculty of Arts and Sciences. Records of Faculty of Engineering, 1986-1994, Accession 2000-A-042
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2029
  - Supporting materials, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Council of Engineering, 1986-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Yale School of Engineering (parts 1 and 2), 1969-2001 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Engineering and Applied Sciences department, undergraduate courses, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Engineering, mechanical, Briggs and Stratton Grant (Dunham laboratory), 1988 April (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mechanical engineering, space shuttle experiments (NASA), Professor Apfel, 1991 February (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Engineering, mechanical, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Engineering, "twilight" graduate courses, Charles K. Kao, 1986 April (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Engineering, juggling robots, 1991 January-February (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photographic assignments, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Engineering, miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Engineering, microelectronics center microfabrication facilities, 1988 September (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Engineering, microelectronics center, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Engineering, open house, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Engineering, hovercraft with students (dupont challenge), 1992 February (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Engineering, electronic, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Engineering, electrical, Hewlett-Packard and Thomson Components, Mostek, Tom Cunningham, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Engineering, electrical; Morse teaching center, dedication and reception, 1988 December (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Engineering and Applied Science, steam locomotive, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Engineering and Applied Science, ITT grant, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Engineering, Microelectronics center, Microfabrication facility, Nanometrics gift, 1988 October (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Engineering, council of; YSEA, inc. meeting, 1990 April (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - E.A.S., high school program, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Engineering and Applied Science, first reunion, 1988 April (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Applied Science, Gyrotron, Jay L. Hirschfield, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Engineering, fellowships, IBM graduate, fellowships, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Engineering, equipment, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Engineering, council of receptions, faculty, staff, graduate students, 1991 September (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Engineering, council of; reception, faculty and staff, 1990 September (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Engineering, council of; reception, faculty and staff, 1990 September (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Engineering, council of, newsletter, 1990 January (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Engineering, electrical, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Engineering, design competition, 1991 April (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Engineering, students and their exhibits, 1991 May (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Engineering, council of YSEA, annual meeting, 1992 April (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - (The) fund for Engineering, Yale University final report, 1988 October (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Engineering, School of, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Engineering, alumni day, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Engineering awards, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Engineering, Black Engineer of the Year, awards conference, Baltimore, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Engineering, chemical, dodge lecture (American Institute of Chemical Engineering), January 1987 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Engineering, chemical; Professor Gary L. Haller, July 1989 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Engineering, council of; newsletter, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Photographic assignment, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Photographic assignments, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Engineering, council of; science show, 1989 February (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Engineering, Council of; Yale Science and Engineering Association, Inc., annual dinner and meeting, 1991 April (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Posters made spring 1971 for EDS newsletter (Box 1A, Folder 1)